A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Administrative Functions, RG 4 FA1798
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Communications, 1943-2017; 2; 9.78 Cubic Feet 28 containers
  - Events, 1991-2016; 2.3; 0.57 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 half document box
    - Knight Foundation Year-End Gathering, 2014 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 5468
      Run of show and Banquet Event order for the staff holiday gathering at db Bistro Moderne.
    - Board of Trustees Meeting and Reception at Perez Art Museum Miami, 2014 December 16-2015 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 5492
      Planning documents, invitation, schedules, run of shows, invitation lists and other materials re: planning for the March Board of Trustees meeting and dedication of the Knight Plaza at the Perez Art Museum Miami.
    - Arts Program Receptions, 2015 June 24-November 30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 5564
      Lists winners of the Philadelphia Arts Challenge, 2014-1015; Miami, 2015; and Detroit 2015. Also included is the evite to the Miami event.
    - Rethinking Libraries in the Digital Age Reception, 2015 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 5593
      Draft Run of Show schedule for the reception, which featured a talk by John Palfrey, a book signing, and introductory remarks and closing Q & A by Alberto Ibarguen and John Palfrey. Also includes an email invitation to the event.
    - Knight Arts Challenge St. Paul Winners Reception 2015 & 2016 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 5580
      Programs include a list of the winners. Information included is Project Name, Award Amount, Recipient, and brief project description.
    - Knight Holiday Party, 2015 December (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 5631
      Invitation to the Knight Foundation Holiday Gathering for staff and trustees at db Bistro Moderne.
    - Knight Foundation Grand Openings, 2015 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 5598
      Six images of ribbon cuttings at grand openings of KF sponsored events. Features Board of Trustees, Dennis Scholl, Donna Frisby-Greenwood, and Alberto Ibarguen. Dates vary - scanned copies of KF images.
    - Knight Arts Challenge Akron Winners Reception 2016, 2016 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 5917
      Program includes a list of the winners. Information included is Project Name, Award Amount, Recipient, and brief project description. 4 copies
    - Knight Holiday Party, 2016 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 5913
      Invitation to the Knight Foundation Holiday Gathering for staff and trustees at Ball & Chain Miami
  - New Releases, 1975-2017; 2.4; 2.85 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes and 1 half-letter document box
    News releases originating from Knight Foundation between 1975 and 2000 document significant program activities and grants, staff appointments, and trustee activities. News releases produced by other organizations about Knight Foundation activities between 1982 and 2000 are also included in this series.
    - Knight Foundation, 1975-2017; 2.4.1
      - Index of News Releases, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 211
        List of Knight Foundation-issued news releases organized by category (Arts & Culture, Community Initiatives, Education, Emergency Grants, Hurricane Grants, Journalism, Miami Grants, Miscellaneous, Staff Appointments, Trustee News).
      - News Releases, 1975 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 212
        News release issued by Knight Foundation re: Journalism grant to Stanford University and other grants made in 1975. Memo by Ben Maidenburg attached re: the release.
      - News Releases, 1980 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
        Knight File Number - 213
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: miscellaneous grant awards, election of Barbara Knight Toomey and Gordon Heffern as trustees. 2 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1981 April 6-July 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 214
        News release issued by Knight Foundation re: grant to Philadelphia College of Art, miscellaneous grants, election of James L. Knight as Chairman. 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
        Knight File Number - 215
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Journalism grants, Staff appointments (C.C. Gibson's retirement announced), and Trustee News. 3 file folders.
      - Journalism, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 1888
        Press release for Journalism Program, 1988.
      - News Releases, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10-14)
        Knight File Number - 216
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Education grants, Emergency grants, Miami grants, Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, and Staff Appointments (James Spaniolo named vice-president and secretary). 5 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15-19)
        Knight File Number - 217
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Community Initiatives, Education program, Journalism program, announcement of move from Akron to Miami, and Staff Appointments (Timothy Crowe, A. Richardson Love, Penelope McPhee, Sharon Anderson-Nearn). 5 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20-26)
        Knight File Number - 218
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Arts & Culture grants, Community Initiatives, Education program, Journalism program (Knight Chairs), Miami grants, Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, and Trustee News (Lee Hills elected Chairman, Gerald Austen elected Vice-Chairman, election of new trustees Jill Conway and Thomas Johnson). 7 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27-35)
        Knight File Number - 219
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Community Initiatives, Education program, Emergency grants, Hurricane Andrew relief grants, Journalism program, Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, Staff Appointments (Linda Raybin), and Trustee News (Larry Jinks elected to board). 8 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36-44)
        Knight File Number - 220
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Arts & Culture grants (Symphony Initiative), Community Initiatives, Education grants (Excellence in Education), Hurricane Andrew relief grants, Journalism grants, Miami grants, Miscellaneous, Staff Appointments, Trustee News. 9 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
        Knight File Number - 2217
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Arts & Culture and Community Initiatives (immunization initiatives) (3 folders)
      - News Releases, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
        Knight File Number - 221
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Education grants (Excellence in Education), Journalism grants, Miami grants, Staff appointments, Trustee News (election of Barbara Knight Toomey and Larry Jinks). 5 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6-12)
        Knight File Number - 222
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: Arts & Culture (Magic of Music Initiative), Community Initiatives, Education (Different Ways of Knowing), Journalism (Knight Chairs), Miami grants, Staff Appointments, Trustee News (John Ong and Rolfe Neill elected to Board of Trustees). 7 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13-19)
        Knight File Number - 209
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: grants awarded in Arts & Culture, Community Initiatives, Education, Journalism, Miami grants; also Staff Appointments, and Trustee News. 7 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 20-25)
        Knight File Number - 210
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: grants in Arts & Culture, Community Initiatives, Education, Emergency Grants, and Journalism; also included are Staff Appointments. 6 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26-31)
        Knight File Number - 1076
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation re: grants in Arts & Culture, Community Initiatives, Education, Journalism, staff and trustee appointments (incuding the election of Mike Maidenberg to the Board), Emergency Grants (Hurricane Georges) and Presidential Leadership grant program.
      - News Releases, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32-34)
        Knight File Number - 208
        News releases issued by Knight Foundation, including information about staff (new CFO Beatriz Clossik) and trustee appointments (John W. Rogers, Jr.), and a notice that Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics recommendations are available on the internet. Also releases concerning programs (IDEAS Fund NewTown Macon partnership, and endowed chairs in broadcast journalism (a new focus for KF. Grantees were Syracuse, Northwestern, and the new Western Center for Specialized Journalism). (three folders)
      - News Releases, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        Knight File Number - 1517
        Releases include grant to Cornell's John S. Knight Writing Program, the death of Lee Hills, Knight Commission, Knight grants, and Journalism initiatives. Many of the releases are undated.
      - News Releases, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        Knight File Number - 2721
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, staff changes, and the Knight Commission.
      - News Releases, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 2722
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, staff changes, the Knight web site, and the Knight Commission.
      - News Releases, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 2723
      - News Releases, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 2724
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, staff changes, and the Knight Commission. Several releases are undated.
      - News Releases, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
        Knight File Number - 3024
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, community partners initiatives and advisory committees, the Knight Commission and staff changes. [2 folders]
      - Launch of the Carnegie-Knight Initiative on the Future of Journalism Education, 2005 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 3367
        Press kit contains Carnegie Corporation and KF releases announcing the launch; a statement by Vartan Gregorian; schedule for press briefing and speaker biographies; "Welcome to Knight Foundation's Journalism Initiatives Program"; and a booklet, "Improving the Education of Tomorrow's Journalists", prepared by the Carnegie Corporation.
      - News Releases, 2006 January 6-December 22 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
        Knight File Number - 3862
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, community partners initiatives and advisory committees, the Knight Commission and staff changes (2 folders). Also includes a speech delivered by Alberto Ibarguen on "A Foundation for the Future of Journalism and Communities" (February 9, 2006)
      - Carnival Center for the Performing Arts Press Kit, 2006 July 19-September 24 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 3802
        Press kit contains news release re: Miami Performing Arts Center Foundation Accepts Landmark Multimillion-Dollar Naming Gifts From Carnival Corporation and Knight Foundation. The Center was renamed Carnival Center for the Performing Arts and the Concert Hall became the John S. and James L. Knight Concert Hall. Included in the press kit is the news release, a "who's who", a fact sheet about the Carnival Center, and lists of donors and directors. Also included is a newspaper special section produced by the Carnival Center for the Performing Arts with articles about donors and artists. The Knight Foundation has a full page ad on the back.
      - Knight Center for International Media, Univeristy of Miami, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 4403
        Press kit contains news release re: creation of the Knight Center for International Media at the University of Miami. Includes a press release, fact sheet, a list of the Knight Chairs in Journalism, several brochures, and bio of Alberto Ibarguen.
      - Knight News Challenge Press Kit, 2007 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 4398
        Press kit contains news release re: Knight News Challenge First-Year Winners Announced Today at E&P/Mediaweek Interactive Media Conferece; Fact Sheet, information on Knight Foundation and other digital media grants it has made; and a list of the winners, with bios, projects, photos and contact information.
      - News Releases, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 4059
        Releases re: community initiatives. appointment of community advisors, staff changes, grants and initiatives and Knight Commission.
      - News Releases, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 4257
        Releases re: grants, journalism initiatives, community partners initiatives and advisory committees. Includes releases on initiatives involving Ashoka, New Americans initiative, OneCommunity initiative, Knight Commission on the Information Needs of Communities in a Democracy, appointment of Kristen Taylor as Online Community Manager, Knight News Innovation EPpy Award, the Knight Arts Partnership, the Newseum Museum in Washington, DC the Common Good Collaborative, renovation of the John S. and James L. Knight Nonprofit Center in Biloxi, MS; the expansion of the Carnegie-Knight initiative to transform journalism education in the U.S. and a grant to NewsU and The Poynter Institute. Also Web Foundation news coverage.
      - News Releases, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 4433
        Releases re: Knight Creative Communities Institute to focus on Tallahassee's Economy; Knight Arts Challenge (includes ad and card); Shorty Award winners (bloggers on Twitter); Media Innovation Initiatives card; Announcement re: Finalists in Knight Arts Challenge; KF President Testifies before Congress on Future of Journalism; Knight Journalism Fellows Named at Stanford for the 2009-2010 academic year; new investigative reporting initiative; 2009 Knight News Challenge Winners; competition for ideas to help revitalize neighborhood in Macon, GA; Knight News Challenge; Soul of the Community findings; Knight brothers documentary; Knight Arts Challenge; Knight Arts Partnership's haiku contest; Knight Neighborhood Challenge Grants to benefit College Hill, Georgia; winners of the Knight Arts Challenge in Miami; the International Center for Journalism; USA Knight Fellows: The Huffington Post Investigative Fund; and the Library Initiative.
      - News Releases, 2010 January-August (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
        Knight File Number - 4679
        Releases re: Community Foundation Initiative; Cambridge Associates' Kevin Stephenson joins Web Foundation Board; $6 million KF award to extend high-impact journalism fellowships and create Chinese-language service on IJNet.org; Teach for America to More Than Triple Number of its Miami Teachers with the Help of a $6 Million Knight Foundation Grant; National Contest Calls on Community Foundations for Local Information Experiments; New Board Chair Takes Helm at Knight Foundation; Knight Foundation Announces Winners of 2010 News Challenge; Knight Foundation Announces $2 Million Grant from Google, etc. (3 folders - folders 1 and 2 in box 4, folder 3 in box 5)
      - News Releases, 2010 September-December (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - News Releases, 2011 January 10-December 21 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
        Knight File Number - 4894
        Releases re: Haitian Earthquake relief; Knight Arts Challenge; Miami International Film Festival; winners of the Knight/NEA Community Arts Journalism Challenge; and personnel changes at KF. (2 folders)
      - News Releases, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
        Knight File Number - 5206
        Release re: KF honors Bill Friday with $25,000 contribution to scholarship fund in his name. Friday died October 12, 2012. He was formerly co-chair of the KCIA. Also web announcements re: Data-Driven Strategy in the Social Sector webinar, launch of the KF Prototype Fund, Knight News Challenge: Health winners announced; and the Knight Arts Challenge. (2 folders)
      - News Releases, 2013 January 4-December 16 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
        Knight File Number - 5459
        Releases re: Challenges, KF programs and initiatives, reports and personnel changes. (2 folders)
      - News Releases, 2014 January 13-December 4 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
        Knight File Number - 5460
        Releases re: Challenges, KF programs and initiatives, reports and personnel changes. Of special note is information pertaining to the bankruptcy of Detroit. (2 folders)
      - News Releases, 2015 January 5-December 18 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
        Knight File Number - 5479
        Releases re:grants and personnel changes. (2 folders)
      - News Releases, 2016 January 12 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 5900
        Releases re:grants and personnel changes.
      - News Releases, 2017 August 14 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 5899
      - News Releases, 2017, 2017 October 4 (Box 7)
        Knight File Number - 5910
        Releases re:Knight Foundation names 29 winning ideas in 2917 St. Paul Knight Arts Challenge. a community wide initiative funding projects that engage and enrich St. Paul through the arts.
      - News Match opens with $3 million in matching support for nonprofit newsrooms across the country., 2017 October 4 (Box 7)
        Knight File Number - 5908
        News Match opens with $3 million in matching support for nonprofit newsrooms across the country. This week marks the launch of News Match, a $3 million collaboration between Democracy Fund, Knight Foundation and the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation to support nonprofit news organizations that play a vital role informing the public and holding those in power accountable.
      - Knight Foundation donates $2.5 million for hurricane recovery in Puerto Rico, U.S. Virgin Islands, 2017 October 5 (Box 7)
        Knight File Number - 5911
        Knight Foundation donates $2.5 million for hurricane recovery in Puerto Rico, U.S. Virgin Islands.
    - Other, 1982-2008; 2.4.2
      - News Releases, 1982 June 14-November 23 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
        Knight File Number - 223
        News releases re: Knight Foundation grants issued by: Akron Area Foodbanc (Community Initiatives) and Stanford University (Journalism). 2 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 224
        News release issued by Philadelphia College of Art re: Knight Foundation grant (Arts & Culture). 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1985 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 225
        News release issued by Knight-Ridder Newspapers re: transfer of stock to Knight Foundation from John S. Knight Estate. 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1987 August 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 226
        News release issued by University of Maryland College of Journalism re: Knight Center for Specialized Journalism (Journalism Program). 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 227
        News release issued by Stanford University News Service re: John S. Knight Distinguished Lecture. 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1989 March 27-December 1 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
        Knight File Number - 228
        News releases issued by: Centre College (Education); University of Missouri, MIT, and Wayne State University (Journalism) and University of Akron (Miscellaneous). 3 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1990 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 2634
        News release issued by: Florida AMU (Journalism) 1 file folder.
      - News Releases, 1991 June 26-November 27 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
        Knight File Number - 229
        News releases issued by: The American Federation of Arts (Arts & Culture), Millsaps College, Valparaiso University, Lafayette College, Bucknell University (Education), and University of Missouri (Journalism). 3 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1992 January 14-December 22 (Box 1, Folder 14-17)
        Knight File Number - 230
        News releases issued by: The American Federation of Arts, The New Theatre, The Curtis Institute of Music, and The National Trust for Historic Preservation (Arts & Culture), Local Initiatives Support Corporation, The College of St. Catharine, Greater Miami Neighborhoods, American Red Cross, Wichita Public Library, Wichita Children's Home, Richland County Public Library (Community Initiatives), University of Notre Dame, Education Alternatives (Education), Inter-American Press Institute, University of Maryland, University of Missouri, and the World Press Institute at Macalester College (Journalism). 4 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1993 January 21-October 8 (Box 1, Folder 18-22)
        Knight File Number - 231
        News releases issued by: Arts & Culture (National Trust for Historic Preservation, Mid America Arts Alliance, Georgia Museum of Art); Community Initiatives (Cities in Schools, American Red Cross, Reading is Fundamental); Education (Davidson College); Journalism (American Press Institute, Dow Jones Newspaper Fund, Duke University, Columbia University), Emergency (Florida International University - Hurricane Andrew). 5 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1994 January 3-October 3 (Box 1, Folder 23-26)
        Knight File Number - 232
        News releases issued by: Science Museum of Minnesota, New World Symphony, Cleveland Orchestra (Arts & Culture), Kids Voting, The Miami Project to Cure Paralysis, March of Dimes, Elizabeth Blackwell Health Center for Women, The United Way, National Center for Family Literacy, Junior League of Miami, Community Foundation for Palm Beach and Martin Counties (Community Initiatives), American Press Institute, Pennsylvania State University, University of Maryland, Michigan State University, Kettering Foundation, and Knight International Press Fellowship Program (Journalism), Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics. 4 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1995 March 9-October 5 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
        Knight File Number - 233
        News releases issued by: Florida Department of State, Museum Loan Network, Philadelphia Orchestra, New Theatre (Arts & Culture), Volunteer Services of Manatee County, Kids Voting, African American Community Endowment Fund (Community Initiatives), Stetson University, Wildacres Leadership Initiative, Congreso de Latinos Unidos (Education), Duke University, University of Missouri, University of Maryland, American Press Institute, Kettering Foundation News, Southern Scholarship Foundation, University of Texas, Yale Law School (Journalism). 4 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1996 February 20-December 20 (Box 1, Folder 31-35)
        Knight File Number - 234
        News releases issued by: Arts & Culture (Museum Loan Network, Arts and Services for Disabled, Saint Louis Symphony, Kansas City Symphony); Community Initiatives (National Urban League, Kids Voting, The Colorado Trust); Education (Summit Education Initiative, The Gar Foundation, Communities in Schools); Journalism (American Press Institute, University of North Carolina Chapel Hill, Northwestern University, University of Texas); and Miscellaneous (National Freedom of Information Coalition, Independent Sector). 5 file folders.
      - News Releases, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36-40)
        Knight File Number - 1688
        News releases on Knight Foundation grants in Community Initiatives, Arts and Culture, Education, and Journalism, from outside sources, 1997. 4 folders.
      - News Releases, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 41)
        Knight File Number - 1528